华纳兄弟出品
不可饶恕
她是一个没什么前途的年轻女人
当她嫁给威廉.芒尼的时候,
她妈妈的心都碎了
威廉.芒尼 -
一个臭名远扬的窃贼,
谋杀犯,
以邪恶与放纵出名
她死的时候,
没有如其母所想死于丈夫之手
1878年,
她死于天花.
怀俄明州 大威士忌镇 1880年
真小!
lt's small!
不,求你了,不要!
No, please. No! Please!
戴维
Davey!
快过来,小子!
Come running, lad!
-快停下!  -操你妈的臭婊子!
-Stop! -Brand you like a damn steer!
-婊子!   -不,求你了!
-Bitch! -No. Please!
抓住这个婊子!抓住他!
Hold the bitch! Go on, hold her!
抓住她,操,我要把她的奶头切下来!
Hold her, damn it, or l'll cut her tits off!
快去叫斯金尼!快!
Go get Skinny! Quick!
迈克,不要!
Mike, don't!
斯金尼
Skinny!
觉得这好玩吗?
Think it's funny?
斯金尼,拿着枪!
Skinny, get the gun!
离她远点儿,牛仔
Get off of her, cowboy.
-不让你管这事儿?  -你知道斯金尼的为人
-Wouldn't let you settle it? -You know Skinny.
他说他要亲自毙了他两个王八蛋.我对他说：你不能
He says he'll shoot them. l says, ''You can't. ''
他说：去叫小比尔.我说：他在睡觉呢
He says, ''Get Little Bill. '' l says, ''He's sleeping. ''
他说：小比尔不会管的.他不久就能动手杀那两人了
He says, ''He don't care. '' He'll shoot them boys soon.
她要死了?
She going to die?
她没事了
She's going to live.
她什么也偷,甚至连碰都没过他的钱袋
She didn't steal nothing or touch his poke.
她只是看他的小“老二”时...
When she seen his teensy little pecker. . .
.....笑了几声.她什么也不知道
. . .she giggled. She didn't know no better.
你要把他们吊死,小比尔
You can hang them, Little Bill.
去办公室把鞭子拿来
Step over to the office and get the bullwhip.
他们做了这事,就挨一顿鞭打?
A whipping's all they get after what they done?
-鞭打也算大刑了,爱丽丝.  -但是他们做的--
-lt ain't no little thing, Alice. -But what they done--
闭嘴!
Shut up!
-抽他们一顿可解决不了这事儿?  -解决不了?
-Whipping ain't going to settle this. -No?
这有一份我和那毁容妓女黛利拉·菲茨杰拉德的合同
Here's a contract between me and Delilah Fitzgerald, the cut whore.
我从波士顿把她买回来,出了全部费用
l brought her from Boston, paid her expenses and all.
我这份合同就代表了一项现金投资
l got a contract that represents an investment of capital.
财产
Property.
被损坏的财物
Damaged property.
就像我挑了他们马的脚筋
Like if l hamstrung one of their ponies.
你觉得以后没人愿玩她了?
You think nobody'll fuck her now?
见鬼,谁愿意!
Hell, no!
没人愿意付钱玩她!
Won't pay to do it!
她能打扮起来,但谁愿意付钱玩一个毁了容的妓女?
She can clean, but nobody's going to pay good money for a cut-up whore!
你们两个小子犯了错.有自己的马吗?
You boys are off the Bar T. Got your own string of ponies?
是的,我有四匹
Yeah, l got four.
六匹
Six.
你们案情简单,就不用审判了,没问题吧?
You just as soon not have a trial, no fuss?
没问题
No, sir.
好的
All right.
你毁的容
You did the cutting.
秋天之前,你带五匹马来这还给斯金尼
Come the fall, you bring in five ponies to Skinny here.
五匹?
Five?
还有你.你带两匹来
And you! You bring in two.
-你们要交出来做补偿,明白吗?  -是的,长官
-You give them over, hear? -Yes, sir.
这鞭子
The bullwhip.
现在我们可能不需要这玩意了
Maybe we don't need this now.
让我告诉你,如果春天斯金尼还没拿到那些马....
Let me tell you, come the spring, Skinny don't have those ponies. . . .
-我一定会来找你们.  -你不抽他们一顿?
-l'll come looking for you. -You ain't whipping them?
我用罚款代替了,爱丽丝
l fined them instead, Alice.
斯金尼得到了马匹,这就完事了?
Skinny gets some ponies and that's it?!
这不公平
That ain't fair.
That ain't fair!
今晚的血腥这不够多吗?
Haven't you seen enough blood tonight?
行了,爱丽丝!
Hell, Alice!
情况有点不同,他们又不是什么浪人或坏男人
lt ain't like they was tramps or loafers or bad men.
他们只不过...
They were just. . .
...是努力工作的孩子,偶尔犯了傻
. . .hardworking boys that were foolish.
-为了一个不干净的女人就鞭打她   -我们妓女?
-lf they was given over to wickedness-- -Like whores?
去照顾黛利拉吧
Tend to Delilah.
去吧
Go ahead.
我出85美元
l got $85.
我不知道
l don't know.
如果黛利拉自己都不太在意的话,我们干嘛这么生气?
lf Delilah doesn't care, what are we so riled up about?
就是因为我们能让这些臭烘烘的傻瓜像马一样的骑在我们身上...
Just because we let them smelly fools ride us like horses. . .
...但我们决不允许他们像对马一样对待我们
. . .don't mean we let them brand us like horses.
可能因为我们是可怜的妓女,但是,上帝,我们不是任人驱使的马匹
Maybe we ain't nothing but whores, but, by God, we ain't horses!
我出112美元
l got $1 1 2.
这是我所有的了
That's everything.
你出多少,费思?
And you, Faith?
200美元
200.
240美元
$240.
天呀!这么多钱?
Jesus, Faith! What you been doing?
让斯金尼尝了什么甜头?
Been giving Skinny something special?
她笑了
She laughs.
加上凯特、苏姬,还有我的--
With what Kate got, and Silky, me and Little Sue--
不够
lt ain't enough.
不一定
Not yet, maybe.
你看起来可不像..
You don't look like no rootin'-tootin' . . .
...混蛋的冷血杀手
. . .son of a bitching cold-blooded assassin.
你说什么?
Say what?
我猜你就是威廉.芒尼先生吧
My guess is you call yourself Mr. William Munny.
先生,你一定是找错人了
You have me confused with someone else, mister.
也就是那个在大湖县杀死查理·佩珀的家伙
The same who shot Charlie Pepper in Lake County?
爸爸!
Pa!
怎么了,儿子?
What's up, son?
两头公猪得了热病
Two more hogs got the fever.
你杀了查理·佩珀
You shot Charlie Pepper.
在密西西比,你杀了威廉·哈维并抢了那火车
You killed William Harvey and robbed that train in Missouri.
等一下,先生
Hold on, mister.
儿子,把那病猪隔离开
Son, get those hogs separated there.
潘妮,帮帮你哥哥
Penny, help your brother.
那只也病了
That one's sick too.
我们进屋谈
We'll talk inside.
你是皮特·索托的侄子?
So you're Pete Sothow's nephew?
我还以为你是为了旧日的过节来杀我的呢
l thought you'd come to kill me for something l'd done in the old days.
我能杀你
l could have.
容易
Easy.
我想可能是吧
l guess maybe so.
你可不像什么冷血杀手
You don't look like no meaner-than-hell, cold-blooded, damn killer.
可能吧
Maybe l ain't.
皮特说你是活在这世上的最卑鄙的混蛋
Uncle Pete says you was the meanest goddamn son-of-a-bitch alive.
如果我想要个杀人的伙伴..
And if l wanted a partner for a killing. . .
...你是最坏的
. . .you were the worst one.
其实是最好的
Meaning the best.
你像雪一样冷酷无情...
On account as you're as cold as snow. . .
...从不恐惧,脆弱
. . .and don't have no weak nerve nor fear.
皮特这样说?
Pete said that?
是的,他就是这么说的
Yeah, he did.
我自己也是个杀手...
l'm a killer myself, except. . .
...只不过没你杀人多,我还年轻呗
. . .l haven't killed as many as you because of my youth.
斯科菲尔德小子.他们就是这么叫我的
Schofield Kid, that's what they call me.
为什么?
Why?
你来自斯科菲尔德?
You from Schofield?
不,只因为..
No, it's on account. . .
...我的斯科菲尔德型的史密斯&维森手枪
. . .of my Schofield model Smith & Wesson pistol.
怎么样,威尔?
How about it, Will?
什么怎么样?
How about what?
做我的搭档怎么样?
How about being my partner?
我要向北穿过奈厄布拉勒到怀俄明去杀这两个无恶不做的牛仔
l'm heading north through Niobrara to 怀俄明 to kill two no-good cowboys.
他们做了什么?
For what?
伤害了一位女士.把她的脸毁了
For cutting up a lady. Cut up her face.
把她的脸划伤了.把她的眼睛挖出来了
Cut her eyes out, cut her ears off.
他们甚至还砍了她的乳头
They even cut her teets.
天啊!
Jesus!
1000美元的赏金,威尔
$1 ,000 reward, Will.
一人一半
500 apiece.
我拉不动那些该死的肥猪!
l can't move those damn pigs!
不要讲粗话.尽力做就行了
Watch your cussing, will you? Do the best you can with it.
一会儿去水泵那儿洗干净.快去
Then go to the pump and get cleaned up. Come on.
我已经不是杀手了,小子
l ain't like that anymore, Kid.
岁月无情摧人老呀
lt was whiskey done it as much as anything else.
我已经十年没干过了
l ain't had a drop in over 1 0 years.
我的妻子帮我改邪归正了
My wife, she cured me of that.
让我不再喝酒,不再做坏事
Cured me of drinking and wickedness.
你看起来好象不富
You don't look so prosperous.
用你的一半赏金,你可以给她买身衣服
You could buy her a new dress with your half.
如果我们杀了他们,你就能买--
lf we kill them, you can buy--
她已经去世了
She's passed on.
到现在已经三年了
Been gone near 3 years now.
不要告诉别人赏金的事.我可不想别人和我争
Don't tell no one about the reward. l don't need other gunmen collecting.
我们这儿没别人
We don't see no one out here.
如果你改变主意,到正西方..
lf you was to change your mind, l'll be riding due west. . .
...去怀俄明铁路的边找我
. . .for the trail into Wyoming.
走,让我们把这些猪分开
Come on, let's separate those hogs.
还有两个
Two others.
我想他们得到热病
l think they got the fever.
真花了不少时间
Took you boys a while.
再多过几天,我就要报告治安官了
A few more days and l was going to call on the sheriff.
怎么了?
How about that?
河里涨水了.我们渡不过去
The river was all swelled up. Couldn't cross it.
我相信.斯里宾,把这些马带到马房去
l bet. Sleepy, get them horses to the livery.
尼尔,把这匹带到后面去
Neil, take that one over around the back.
噢,这里有个美人
Now there's a beauty.
我已经给你两匹了.这匹可不是你的
You got two of mine. This one here ain't yours.
我们知道
We'll see about that.
混蛋!离这儿远点!
Bastards! Get out of town!
你们都是混蛋!
You are very sick sons of bitches!
不要再回来,屠夫!
Don't come back, butcher!
这匹马...
This here pony. . .
..给那个被我伙伴伤害的女士
. . .l brung for the lady my partner cut.
她是最好的
She's the best.
比我给他的强多了
Better than what l gave him.
她可以卖掉这匹马...
She can sell her. . .
..或做其它什么的
. . .or do what she wants.
一匹马?她的容貌都毁了,你给她一匹脏马?
A pony? She ain't got no face left, you give her a mangy pony?
她不脏!
She ain't mangy!
快滚!
Get out of here!
我们不需要你的怜悯!
We don't need your goddamn charity!
滚出这个镇子,永远不要回来!
Get out of our town and don't come back!
滚出这个镇子!
Get out of our town!
老爸以前是个杀手?
Did Pa use to kill folks?
我得告诉你,你妈喜欢我送的花
l could tell your ma liked those flowers l gave her.
他不再是匹驯马了.他已经没感觉了
He ain't a saddle horse no more. Ain't used to the feel.
照顾好你姐姐,儿子
Take care of your sister, son.
如果有必要就杀一些鸡.把那些病猪隔离
Kill a few chickens if you must. Keep those hogs with the fever separate.
如果有问题,去内德·洛根家找两棵树萨利
lf you have any problem, go see Sally Two Trees at Ned Logan's.
很久没骑马了
Ain't been in the saddle myself in a while.
从我年轻时,这马就跟着我了
She's getting even with me for the sins of my youth.
那时候我很年轻,还没遇到你妈妈...
ln my youth before l met your dear departed ma. . .
...也很虚弱,喜欢虐待动物
. . .l used to be weak and given to mistreating animals.
这匹马,还有那边的猪...
This horse and those hogs over there. . .
...今天对我这样,都是对我昔日残暴的报应
. . .are getting even for the cruelty l inflicted.
我以前经常骂人....
l used to be able to cuss. . .
鞭打马匹,是你妈妈告诉我做错了
. . .and whip a horse, but your ma showed me the error of my ways.
我两个星期后回来
l'll be back in two weeks.
记住你们亲爱的妈妈在天堂里看着你们呢
Remember the spirit of your dear departed ma watches over you.
-你们怎么弄到的钱?  -我们一分也没有
-Where'd you get the money? -We ain't got any!
-你不是告诉那些牛仔你有吗?  -我们骗人的
-You told them cowboys you had! -We was lying!
骗人?
Lying?
有人真来拿赏金,你怎么办?
What'll you do if somebody comes to collect?
你和他们做一千次?
You going to hump them a thousand times?
这些来拿钱的人可受不了你一分没有
The kind of people who come for it won't tolerate you not having it!
他们不仅仅会毁了你的容!
They won't just cut up your face!
你们这些愚蠢的婊子
You stupid bitches.
你们这些愚蠢的婊子!
You stupid bitches!
操!
Shit!
该死的.天啊!
Damn it! Jesus!
扎了你的手?
Hit your finger?
你好,斯金尼
Hello, Skinny.
你在这鬼鬼祟祟干什么?
Damn, you snuck up on me.
这屋不错吧?
What do you think of her?
我听过是你自己做了这个屋顶
l heard you done the roof yourself.
屋顶?整个屋都是我做的
Roof? Jesus, l did practically the whole damn thing myself.
罗伯特家的孩子帮我搬搬木头,就这些了
The Roberts boy carried wood for me, but that's all.
那些木头做什么?
What is all that wood?
我在建一个走廊.这样我就能整晚坐在这里...
l'm building a porch so l can sit of an evening. . .
...抽着雪茄,喝着咖啡看日落了
. . .and smoke my pipe and drink coffee and watch the sunset.
到这来就为看这屋一眼?
Came out here just to take a look at her?
-那些妓女!  -怎么了?
-Them whores! -Yeah?
正和那些最近2周来镇上的牛仔们做爱呢
Been humping them cowboys who been in town the last 2 weeks.
真糟糕,斯金尼
Shit, Skinny.
我们有铁路霸主,有养牛霸主
We got railroad barons. We got cattle barons.
你快成我们的第一位台球霸主了
You'll be the first billiard baron.
她们在做爱的时候告诉每个人...
They been humping and telling every bowlegged one of them. . .
...如果有谁杀了弄伤黛利拉的两个牛仔..
. . .they'll pay $1 ,000 to whoever. . .
...她们将出一千美元
. . .kills the two boys that cut up Delilah.
那些牛仔是赶着牛去堪萨斯的吗?是的
Those cowboys are riding that beef down to Kansas and Cheyenne?
有多少时间了,一个星期?
All week long?
我是昨晚才听说的
l didn't hear till last night myself.
这消息现在恐怕已经传到得州
The word's probably got all the way to Texas by now.
在得州,没人能消声匿迹
Nobody'll come clear from Texas.
你确定他们能得那那钱?
You sure they got that money?
女人们喜欢说慌.问她们钱在哪?她们说没有
Women can lie. Ask where the money is, they say they got none.
可能这五个婊子把它们藏了起来
But those five could have squirreled it away. Maybe.
有这么多钱?
That much?
能让那两个牛仔逃之夭夭了
Could run off them two cowboys.
我能让那些妓女快走
l could run off them whores.
那两个牛仔已经早跑了吧
They'll just up and run anyhow, them two.
他们待在T牧场里
They'll stay out at the Bar T.
和他们的朋友在一起
Close to their friends.
该死,要是什么事都没发生就好了
Shit, could be nobody won't come at all.
得走了,我喜欢你的房子
Got to go. l like your house.
那不是...
Well, l'll be. . . .
威尔吗!
lt's Will!
到屋里来躲躲阳光.萨利....
Come in the house out of the sun. Sally. . .
...照顾好威尔的马
. . .see to Will's horse.
你来这干嘛?
What are you doing here?
想着和你再干一票
Just thought l'd drop in on you.
我们可不再是坏人了
We ain't bad men no more.
我们是农民
We're farmers.
如果他们不先去得州,那杀他们可就容易了
Should be easy killing them, if they don't go on down to Texas.
你多长时间没朝人开枪了?九年,十年?
How long since you fired a gun at a man? Nine, ten years?
十一年了
Eleven.
容易?
Easy, huh?
我不知道是不是事情重新变的简单了
l don't know it was all that easy even back then.
我们又年青充满活力了
And we were young and full of beans.
如果你对他们很生气...
lf you was mad at them. . .
我可以看着你打死他们
. . .over some wrong, l could see shooting them.
以前我们为钱而杀人
We done stuff for money before.
我们是这样想的
We thought we did.
那帮小子怎么惹你了?打牌时出老千了?
What'd these fellows do? Cheat at cards?
偷了你的牲口?向有钱人吐口水了?到底是什么?
Steal some strays? Spit on a rich fellow? What?
他们伤害了一个女人
They cut up a woman.
什么?
What?
伤了她的脸,挖了她的眼睛,砍的她的手指,砍了她的乳头
Cut up her face, cut her eyes out, cut her fingers off, cut her tits.
我想除了她的阴部,其余都砍了
Everything but her cunny, l suppose.
我得顽强点儿
l'll be dogged.
想的出他们有多残忍
Guess they got it coming.
当然,威尔...
Of course, Will. . .
如果克劳迪娅还活着,你不会做这事的
. . .if Claudia was alive, you wouldn't do this.
下个星期帮我照顾一下我的小孩怎么样?
Could you look in on my youngsters next week?
有些猪得了热病,他们得把那些猪隔离开
They got some hogs they're trying to separate.
你离开多久?
How long will you be gone?
两个星期吧
Two weeks, l guess.
那小子怎么样?
What's this Kid like?
分三份怎么样?
Three ways?
我看你还是留着那斯宾塞来福枪吧
l see you still have that Spencer rifle.
我还能打中飞鸟的眼睛呢
And l can still knock the eye out of a bird flying.
天啊,威尔!
Jesus, Will!
他肯定是不停的走
He must be moving right along.
我估计明天就能赶上他了
We'll come across him tomorrow, l reckon.
我已经习惯睡在床上了
Kind of got used to my bed.
这可不像个没家的人说的话
This ain't going to be like no home.
那不是我唯一想念的东西
That ain't the only thing l'll miss.
见鬼,对不起
Hell, l'm sorry.
不要烦了.也不件小事
Don't fret it. lt ain't nothing.
她好象不太喜欢...
She don't like it much. . .
...你和我一起骑马离开
. . .you riding off with me.
萨利?白了我一眼
Gave me the evil eye.
你知道的,萨利是印地安人...
You know, Sally's injun. . .
...印地安人都不太友好
. . .and injuns ain't over-friendly.
我没有怪她
l don't blame her.
我不是针对她
l won't hold it against her.
她知道我那时候回来了
She knew me back then.
她知道我是个....
She knew what a. . .
...多么坏的混蛋
. . .no-good son of a bitch l was.
她不允许我那样,所以我改变了
She ain't allowing that l changed.
她没发现我再不是以前那个样了
She don't realize l ain't like that no more.
-你了解女人.  -我变了,内德
-You know women. -l ain't the same, Ned.
克劳迪娅服伺我.在我醉酒后帮我清理
Claudia straightened me up. Cleared me of drinking whiskey and all.
干这票买卖....
Going on this killing. . .
...不是说我要变成过去那样了
. . .don't mean l'll go back to the way l was.
我只是需要钱
Just need the money.
让孩子们有好的生活
Get a new start for them youngsters.
还记着那个被我从嘴里开枪的牲口贩子吧..
Remember that drover l shot in the mouth. . .
...他的牙都从脑后蹦了出来
. . .and his teeth came out the back of his head?
我不时想起他
l think about him now and again.
他不应该被那样打死
He didn't do anything to deserve to get shot.
至少我冷静时想不出他有什么该死的
At least nothing l remembered when l sobered up.
过去你是个疯狂的混蛋
You was one crazy son of a bitch.
没有人喜欢我,所有的人都认为..
No one liked me and the boys all thought. . .
...我会随便杀人
. . .l'd shoot them out of pure meanness.
你和以前不一样了
You ain't like that no more.
老鹰,他讨厌狼吞虎咽
Eagle, he hated my guts.
波那巴特不太理我
Bonaparte didn't think too much of me.
我估计昆西也是
Quincy neither, l reckon.
昆西过去总是看着...
Quincy used to just watch all the time. . .
...吓的要命
. . .scared.
像我说的....
Like l said. . .
...你和以前不一样了
. . .you ain't like that no more.
是的
That's right.
我现在是个平常人
l'm just a fellow now.
我和其它人一样....
l ain't no different than anyone else. . .
...没什么不同
. . .no more.
是哪个混蛋开枪的?是不是哪个英国佬?
What son of a bitch shot him? Was it one of them John Bulls?
不,先生.那准刺客是个法裔绅士
No, sir. The would-be assassin is a gentleman of French ancestry.
看起来是这样.我不想说什么冒犯的话....
Or so it seems. l don't wish to give offense. . .
...但法国人是出名的“剌客一族”
. . .but the French are known to be a race of assassins. . .
...个个都会开枪
. . .who can't shoot worth a damn.
一个法国人就是全体法国人的代表
Any Frenchmen present are excluded, of course.
这儿有个家伙叫吉托.G-U-I-T--
Says here a fellow by the name of Guiteau. G-U-l-T--
这家伙对我来说就是个英国佬
Sure as hell sounds like a John Bull to me.
我还是不想冒犯,但我想建议这个国家选个...
Again, l don't wish to give offense when l suggest this country select. . .
...国王或王后什么的,比选个总统强多了
. . .a king or even a queen, rather than a President.
没人这么快就要刺杀国王或王后
One isn't that quick to shoot a king or a queen.
因为大家要忠于皇室,你说是吧
The majesty of royalty, you see.
可能你不想冒犯,先生....
Maybe you don't wish to give offense, sir. . .
...但你真让人吃不消
. . .but you are giving it pretty thick.
这个国家不需要什么国王、皇后
This country don't need no queens whatsoever.
-当我听到什么国王、皇后的时候   -闭嘴,乔
-When l heard about queens-- -Shut up, Joe.
你有什么问题,瑟斯蒂? 这个小子--
What's wrong with you, Thirsty? This dude--
这家伙是英国人叫鲍勃
Might be that this dude is English Bob.
负责处死那些华工
Works for the railroad shooting Chinamen.
可能他正等着有人惹,他好有借口掏枪....
Might be he's waiting for some cowboy to touch his pistol. . .
...射击呢
. . .so he can shoot him.
他说的对吗,先生?
ls that a fact, mister?
你是英国人鲍勃?
You English Bob?
野鸡
Pheasants.
让我们打点野鸡
Let's shoot some pheasants.
一共十枪
Ten shots.
我们说好了,一只一美元
At, let's say, $1 a pheasant.
我为了女王而射击,你们为了...
l'll shoot for the Queen, and you. . .
...愿为谁就为谁吧
. . .for whomever.
我打了八只,你打了一只
That's eight for me and one for you.
那就是七美元
That comes to seven American dollars.
打的真他妈的好...
Pretty damn good shooting. . .
...真是个英国佬
. . .for a John Bull.
豪无疑问,你的准头被你的悲伤影响了...
No doubt your aim was affected by your grief. . .
...这是对总统受伤的悲伤
. . .over the injury to your President.
是气候的原因.还有这漫长路途的影响
lt's the climate that does it. That, and the infernal distances.
你说什么?
Does what?
导致人们在上层人物开枪
lnduces people to shoot persons in high places.
向真人开枪可不文明
lt's uncivilized shooting persons of substance.
谢谢你
Thank you.
先生,请原谅我
Pardon me, gentlemen.
法律要求你向有关机构交出武器
The law obliges you to surrender sidearms to the proper authorities.
有关机构?
Proper authority?
我可以向你保证：我和的随从,谁也没带武器
l assure you that neither my companion or l carry firearms on our person.
我们依靠的是与人为善...
We rely upon the goodwill of our fellow man. . .
...和处处忍让
. . .and the forbearance of reptiles.
没有武器,混蛋!
Unarmed, my ass!
上帝,天真热!
Christ, it's hot!
如果我中枪了,我宁愿是热天而不是冷天
lf l'm going to get shot, l'd rather it was hot than cold.
在冷天什么东西伤害都加倍.你知道的当伤到你的--
Everything hurts me more when it's cold. You know how if you hit your--
闭嘴,胖子!
Shut up, Fatty!
克莱德回来了
Clyde's back.
-和小比尔一起?  -不
-With Little Bill? -No.
该死!
Shit!
-你们擦了我的雷明顿枪了?  -擦了并已经装药
-You clean my Remington? -Cleaned and loaded.
小比尔在哪?
Where's Little Bill?
在建他的走廊呢
Building his damn porch.
建他的走廊?
Building his porch?
如果你中枪,你愿在热天还是冷天?
lf you got shot, would you want it to be hot or cold?
我宁愿不中枪
l ain't going to get shot.
他来了?
He's coming?
是的,他来了
Of course he's coming.
我已经上过子弹了
l just loaded that.
别人上子弹我信不过
l trust nobody loading my guns if l'm shooting.
他说什么?
What'd he say?
小比尔说他正在建走廊
Little Bill said he was building his porch.
-你看到了吗?  -已经装满了
-You seen that thing? -lt was all loaded.
克莱德,你拿了三支手枪,可只拿了一支步枪
Clyde, you got three pistols and you only got one arm!
我可不想因为没后备枪而送命
l don't want to get killed for lack of shooting back.
他的走廊建的歪歪扭扭!
He don't have a straight angle on that whole porch!
整个房子都是这样
Or the whole house, for that matter!
他是个糟糕的木匠
He is the worst damn carpenter.
他什么也没说?
He didn't say nothing?
只问了一下他们长的什么样
Asked what they looked like.
可能他是个硬汉,但他确实是个糟糕的木匠
Maybe he's tough but he sure ain't no carpenter.
可能他还不是个硬汉
Maybe he ain't so tough.
看起来他害怕了?
Seem like he was scared?
小比尔?他害怕了?
Little Bill? Him scared?
我们从来没见他像今天这样
We never seen him up against any like these ones.
杀手
Killers.
小比尔是从堪萨斯和得州出来的
Little Bill come out of Kansas and Texas, boys.
他什么事没见过
He worked them tough towns.
我也想有点奇怪
Just wondered.
每个人都会害怕
Anybody could be scared.
他不会害怕的
He wasn't scared, boys.
他不是个木匠
He just ain't no carpenter.
王室的尊严....
There's a dignity in royalty. . .
...可以阻止刺杀一类的东西
. . .which precludes the likelihood of assassination.
如果你用枪指着...
lf you pointed a pistol. . .
...君主,你的手就像中风一样颤抖
. . .at a monarch, your hands would shake as if palsied.
我不会用枪指着任何人
l wouldn't point no pistol at nobody.
真聪明
That's a wise policy.
但是,如果你做了,我可以向你保证.对王室的忠诚....
But if you did, l assure you, the sight of royalty. . .
...可以打消你杀戮的念头.你就可以...
. . .would cause you to dismiss thoughts of bloodshed. You would stand. . .
明白那些...
. . .how should l put it. . .
...我敬畏的东西
. . .in awe.
一位总统....为什么要刺杀一位总统
A President. . . . Why not shoot a President?
不用找了
Keep the change.
这个叫草莓爱丽丝的人,再说一次她住在哪?
This Strawberry Alice person, tell me again.
走到街尾,格里利啤酒馆和台球厅旁边就是了
Down the street to Greely's Beer Garden and Billiards Parlor.
你不想打回台球
Say you want a game of billiards.
台球?我不太想打
Billiards? Even though l don't really wish to play?
没关系.1878年时,他们把球桌当木柴烧了
No matter. They burned the table in '78 for firewood.
太对了
Quite right.
比彻姆,先生,来杯茶--
Mr. Beauchamp, l think a cup of tea--
喂,鲍勃
Hello, Bob.
孩子们,这位是英国人鲍勃
Boys, this here is English Bob.
该死!
Shit and fried eggs!
时间过的真快
Been a long time.
不杀中国人了?
Run out of Chinamen?
我还以为你死了呢
l thought that you were dead.
你把你的山羊胡剃了
You've shaved your chin whiskers off.
我正在回味两小时前我喝的汤呢
l was tasting the soup two hours after l ate it.
实际上,我听说你...
Actually, what l heard was you. . .
...喝醉了酒,从马上掉到来
. . .fell off your horse, drunk, of course.
还把脖子折断了
And that you broke your bloody neck.
我自己也听说了
l heard that one myself, Bob.
当时,我还为我就要死了呢
Hell, l even thought l was dead.
直到发现我在内布拉斯加州
Till l found out l was just in Nebraska.
这位是你的朋友?
Who's he?
W.W. 比彻姆
W.W. Beauchamp.
这位是小比尔 达格特
This is Little Bill Daggett.
我的朋友
And friends, of course.
哪的朋友,牛顿还是阿比林的?
From Newton, Hays? From Abilene?
在监狱里的朋友
ln person.
你也为铁路工作?
You work for the railroads too?
不,我写东西
l write.
写信?
Letters?
写书,比尔,是写书
Books, Bill. Books.
实际上...
Actually. . .
...他是我的自传作者
. . .he's my biographer.
要是你,我可不会这么做
l wouldn't do that if l were you.
只是一本书
lt's only a book.
一本书?
A book?
这就是说,你识字了
That means you boys can read.
这就是说你应该看到填外面的布告栏的写着要交出武器的通知了
That means you saw the signs outside town saying surrender your firearms.
就像你跟小安迪说的一样..
But like you told young Andy. . .
...你没带武器,是吧?
. . .you're not armed, are you?
恐怕不是,比尔
Not really, Bill.
只带了把小枪,不会让你担心的
Got a Peacemaker, but that wouldn't worry you, would it?
如果不是你们看到,我想不会发生什么事
lf you don't see it. Or better, if you don't hear it.
我想是的
l'm afraid so, Bob.
我可不喜欢有人随便带着枪
l don't like firearms around.
千万要小心,孩子
Be very careful with it, sonny.
看看比彻姆先生袋子里到底是什么书
See what kind of books Mr. Beauchamp is packing.
小心不要沾上他的尿
Make sure you don't get wet.
没什么
No shit.
都是些文具和这本书
All he's got is writing stuff and this book.
“死鸭”?
''The Duck of Death''?
看清楚
Duke.
“人”
''The Duke. ''
下午好,先生们
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
我想我可以走了吧.等一下
l'll have that .32, Bob.
现在,小比尔. . .
Now, Little Bill. . .
...你让我根本没法对付敌人
. . .you will leave me at the mercy of my enemies.
敌人?
Enemies?
你是不是又在谈什么女王了?
You been talking about the Queen again?
还是在独立日
On lndependence Day?
我想你觉得我正在踢你吧
l guess you think l'm kicking you.
并非如此!
But it ain't so!
我现在是和你聊天!
What l'm doing is talking!
听到没?
Hear?!
和堪萨斯的恶棍聊天!
Talking to all them villains in Kansas!
和密苏里的恶棍聊天!
To all those villains in Missouri!
和那些..
And those villains. . .
...夏延的恶棍!
. . .down in Cheyenne!
我说了这里没什么妓女的赏金!
l'm saying there ain't no whore's gold!
如果有,他们也无论如何...
Even if there was, they don't want to come for it. . .
...不是为此而来的
. . .anyhow!
你们看什么?
What are you looking at?!
该干么干么!
Go on!
管好你们自己!
Mind your own business!
镇上去过么?
Ever go into town?
有时去.把猪卖了,再买点生活用品
On occasion. To sell a hog, pick up supplies.
我是说,再找个女人
l mean, get yourself a woman.
不,我永远不会为这事去镇上的
No, l never go into town for that.
一个像我一样的男人?
A man like me?
只能去花钱买笑
Only woman l could get is one l'd have to pay for.
去嫖妓可不对
That ain't right, buying flesh.
克劳迪娅的灵魂不会希望我去干这事..
Claudia, rest her soul, wouldn't want me doing that. . .
...何况我还是个父亲
. . .me being a father.
你只手淫?
You just use your hand?
我不是太需要
l don't miss it all that much.
该死!有人向我们开枪!
Goddamn! Somebody's shooting at us!
射到你没?
Did it hit you?
从马上掉到来时,我的脑袋摔肿了
l bumped my head falling off my horse.
不向我们开枪了
Ain't shooting at us no more.
好象不是向这边射的
Shooting way over yonder.
他到底在射什么?
What the hell's he shooting at?
鬼才知道,反正不是我们
Beats the hell out of me.
我们可能进了某人的地盘
Reckon we in somebody's field?
我没看见这儿有种着会把东西
l didn't see nothing planted.
又向我们开枪了
Shooting at us again.
他向所有地方开枪
He's shooting at the whole horizon.
等一下.你让我们暴露了!
Wait! You'll mark us!
嗨,小子!
Hey, Kid!
向我们开枪的就是那小子?
That's the Kid shooting at us?
小子,是我!威廉.芒尼!
Kid, it's me! Will Munny!
他向我们开枪做什么?
What the hell's he shooting at us for?
是你吗?
That you?
是的,是我!
Yeah, it's me!
不要再开枪!你听到没有?
Don't go shooting at us no more! You hear me?
你旁边那人是谁,威尔?
Who the hell you got with you, Will?
他是内德·洛根,我的老搭档
lt's Ned Logan, my old partner!
不要再开枪了,听到没有?
Don't go shooting at us, you hear?
我们现在牵着马走过来
We'll get our horses and come on over there.
不要开枪了
You ain't going to shoot, are you?
好的,我不开了!
No, l ain't!
-一里外就发现那匹马了.  -你向我们开枪干什么?
-Chased that horse a damn mile. -What was you shooting at us for?
-我以为你们在跟踪我.  -是的,我是在跟踪你
-l thought you was following me. -We was.
-你说如果我改变主意   -我可没说什么搭档的事吧
-You said if l changed my mind-- -Wasn't nothing said about no partner.
这位内德·洛根
This here's Ned Logan.
这位是斯科菲尔德小子,索托的侄子
He's the Schofield Kid, nephew to Pete Sothow.
我看到你们两位跟踪我.我还以为你们是要来杀我的
l seen two fellows following me. My guess is you come to kill me.
我们可没说过有其它人
We never talked about no other fellow.
那儿有两个牛仔.如果他们找了朋友,我们有三个人就好点儿
There's two cowboys. Better there's three of us, if they got friends.
我能搞定他们两个.不用三个人
l can take care of them two myself. lt don't take three.
内德可是个好枪手,能百步穿杨
Ned's an awful good shot with a rifle. Hit a bird in the eye flying.
怎么样都比你强
Better than you, anyhow.
你还差的远呢
You wasn't even close.
把你的脏手拿开,别碰我的枪
Get your damn hands off my rifle!
只是想为你检查一下.可能有些零件失灵了
Thought l'd check it for you. Maybe something's bent.
没有失灵
lt ain't bent.
刚才你在乱射!
You were shooting all over creation!
你愿意和他分你的一半?
You'll share your half with him?
我想是分三份好
l figure three ways.
你想错了
You figured wrong.
报歉,浪费你的时间了
Sorry l wasted your time, Ned.
你和他一起回去?
You going back with him?
他的我的搭档
He's my partner.
他不去,我也不去
He don't go, l don't go.
好了,三份就三份,一起来吧
What's it come to, three ways?
该死!
Shit!
你在骂什么?
What are you pissing on about?
-还有你在看什么?  -"看"?
-What are you looking at, anyhow? -''Looking at''?
看云,小子
Clouds, Kid.
看着那些云,就知道有风暴要来了
Looking at them on account of we got a storm riding up our ass.
见鬼,我也看到了
Hell, l seen them.
改主意改的真快
You was smart to change your mind.
我真是好枪手
l'm a real good shot with this rifle.
看到那只鹰了吗?
See that hawk?
我能一枪把它打下来
l could hit it with one shot.
我也行,只不过不想浪费子弹
Hell, l could hit it too. lf l didn't mind wasting a shot.
天上没鹰,小子
There ain't no hawk, Kid.
你看不见吗?
You can't see for shit, can you?
看到你的水壶了吗?
See your canteen?
你能看多远?
How far can you see?
-足够远了.  -我们不是在射水壶!到底多远?
-Far enough. -We ain't shooting canteens! How far?
-100码?  -更远
-1 00 yards? -More.
-看到远处那颗胭脂栎了吗?  -操你妈
-See that scrub oak tree yonder? -Fuck you.
-他是瞎着!  -我不是!
-He's blind! -l ain't!
混蛋!
Asshole!
停下!
Hold it!
你到底能看多远?50码?
How far can you see, Kid? 50 yards?
我当然能看50码了,威尔
You bet your ass l can see 50 yards, Will.
打死这个混蛋是足够远了
l can see well enough to shoot this son of a bitch.
停下
Hold on.
听到没,内德?
Hear that, Ned?
这小子能看50码,不错了
Kid can see 50 yards. Fine.
上帝!
Jesus!
50码已经不错了.我们现在走吧
50 yards'll do just fine. Now let's move out.
看起来真是坚苦的战斗
They look like real hard cases, Bob.
你把他们七个都杀了?
Did you kill all seven of them?
还是打伤了?
Or just wing some of them?
封面这个人是你吧?
That you here embalmed on the cover?
“死鸭”?
''The Duck of Death''?
是“人”.是“死人”
lt's the Duke. ''Duke of Death. ''
你总是带着枪,但有七个人...
You always were the hell in Jesus with a pistol, but seven of them?
保护那女的.你是怎么做到的
Protecting that woman. How do you do that?
出版这一行就要求封面故事...
lt's desirable in the publishing business to take a certain. . .
夸张一点儿
. . .liberty when depicting the cover scene.
主要是为了市场
For reasons involving the marketplace--
从我读的来看,内容和封面的画的差不多
From what l read, the writing's not that much different than the picture.
我可以向你保证,Daggett先生...
l can assure you, Mr. Daggett. . .
那件事的描写都是根据目击者所说写成的
. . .that the events described are from eyewitness accounts.
目击者?
Eyewitnesses?
就像那“鸭子”自己,是吧?
Like the Duck himself, l guess.
是“人”
The Duke.
是“鸭”,我说了
Duck, l says.
“"你冒犯了这位女士,科克兰. . .”
'''You have insulted the honor of this beautiful woman, Corcoran. . .'
.....那个鸭子说
. . .said the Duck.
'你必须道歉.'
'You must apologize.'
但双枪科克兰根本不理会
But Two-Gun Corcoran would have none of it.
一边骂着,一边准备掏枪...
Cursing, he reached for his pistols and would have killed him. . .
...但是鸭子速度更快,只见罗轮枪口火光一闪.”
. . .but the Duck was faster and hot lead blazed from his smoking six-guns. ''
我想这就是当时情况的真实描写
l consider that an accurate depiction of events.
我写作时,总是情不自禁的加上一些诗歌的气息
There is a certain poetry to the language which l couldn't resist.
英国人鲍勃杀柯奇·科克兰的那个晚上,
l was in the Blue Bottle Saloon in Wichita. . .
...我也在威奇塔的蓝瓶酒吧
. . .the night English Bob killed Corky Corcoran.
可我没看见你
l didn't see you there.
也没什么女人
Nor no woman.
也没什么双枪将
Nor two-gun shooters.
-什么都没有.  -你在那儿?
-Nor none of this. -You were there?
是的,我在
Yeah, l was there.
第一...
First off. . .
...柯奇从没有有过什么双枪,尽管他好象应该用双枪
. . .Corky never carried two guns, though he should have.
他被叫做双枪科克兰呀
He was called Two-Gun Corcoran.
有很多人叫他双枪,不是因为他总带着两把手枪
A lot of folks did call him Two-Gun, but not because he had two pistols.
是因为他的老二....
lt was because his dick. . .
...比他那把沃克自动手枪还长
. . .was longer than the barrel on his Walker Colt.
他做过的冒犯别人的事就是....
Only insulting he did was stick it into a French lady. . .
...浑身汗臭的干了一个法国娘们
. . .that he was sweet on.
当柯奇走进蓝瓶酒吧,还不知道是怎么回事的时候...
When Corky walked into the Blue Bottle and before he knew what's what. . .
...鲍勃就向他开了一枪,但没有射中,因为鲍勃醉的太厉害了
. . .Bob takes a shot at him! And misses, he's so damn drunk.
那子弹吓坏了柯奇.但他做了一件错事
That bullet whizzing by panicked Corky. He did the wrong thing.
他太着急了,竟然击中了自己了脚指
He hurried and shot his damn toe off.
同时,鲍勃...
Meantime, Bob here. . .
...认真的瞄准,又开了一枪...
. . .aims real good and squeezes off another. . .
....但他又射失了,他还是太醉了!他射到的是一面1000美元的镜子!
. . .but he misses, he's still so drunk! Hits a $1 ,000 mirror over the bar.
那死野做的不错...
The Duck of Death is as good as dead. . .
...就是因为柯奇太逊了
. . .because Corky does it right.
他这次瞄的很准
He aims real careful.
-不慌不忙.  -然后
-No hurry. -And?
那把沃克自动手枪竟然在柯奇手里爆炸了,这是那种枪的普遍缺点
That Walker Colt blew up in his hand, a failing common to that model.
如果柯奇一直都带两把枪的吧,他就能...
lf Corky'd had two guns instead of a big dick, he would've been there. . .
...一直站在那儿战斗了
. . .to defend himself to the end.
等一下
Wait a minute.
鲍勃杀柯奇是在柯奇甚至没有....
English Bob killed him when he didn't even have. . . .
鲍勃可不会等柯奇再长出一只新手
Bob wasn't going to wait for Corky to grow a new hand.
他慢慢的走过去...
No, he just walked over there real slow. . .
...因为他醉了...
. . .because he was drunk. . .
...一枪击中了他的肝脏
. . .and shot him through the liver.
睡在石头上真难受!
Don't like rocks on my dadgum back!
-真想念我的床.  -你昨晚就是这么说的
-l sure do miss my bed. -You said that last night.
昨晚我说我想念我老婆.今晚我说我想念我的床
Last night l said l missed my wife. Tonight l just miss my dadgum bed!
明晚你就会想念你的屋顶了
You'll miss your dadgum roof next, l suppose.
该死!
Shit!
杰克逊县的那事...
That business up in Jackson County. . .
...是不是真的发生过?
. . .that really happen?
是不是像人们传说的那样?
The way they say it happened?
什么事?
What business?
有两个治安官有枪紧紧的指住你
There's two deputies up close pointing their rifles right at you.
马上就要把你干掉
Got you dead to rights.
你突然掏出枪,把那两个家伙都打飞了
You pulled out your pistol and blew them to hell.
仅仅是一个掏枪的动作
Only took a scratch yourself.
皮特说他从来没见过...
Uncle Pete never seen nothing like it. . .
...这么干净利索的身手
. . .shooting your way out of that scrape.
我不记的了
l don't recollect.
你不记的了?
You don't recollect?
是的
Right.
内德. .
Ned. . .
...你杀过多少人?
. . .how many men you killed?
你不准备回答问题吗?
Aren't you going to answer?
这和你有什么关系?
What the hell's that to you?
因为我们要一起拼杀,所以我想知道我和什么样的人在一起
To know the kind of fellow l'm riding with, in case we get into a scrape.
小子,你杀过多少人?
How many men you killed, Kid?
5个
Five.
多少?
How many?
5个!
Five!
我杀了五个人
l done killed five of them.
其中有个是墨西哥人.他想用刀捅我
That's including a Mexican. He come after me with a knife.
收声吧,快休息
Why don't you shut up? Get some rest.
你们这些人一天到晚像老母鸡一样想入非非
You boys are as crotchety as a couple of old hens.
实际上,科克兰先生比“鸭子”--
Actually, then, Mr. Corcoran was faster on the draw than the Duck--
英国人鲍勃先生速度更快?
Than English Bob?
更快?但速度是他的弱点
Faster? Faster was his mistake.
如果他不着急,他也不会打中自己的脚指
lf he hadn't rushed, he wouldn't have shot himself in the toe.
那他早就把老鲍勃给杀了
He would've killed old Bob.
作为一个好枪手,出手迅速..
Being a good shot, being quick with a pistol. . .
也可能不是什么好事,关键是要头脑冷静
. . .don't do no harm, but it don't mean much next to being cool-headed.
如果一个家伙不慌不忙....
A man who'll keep his head, not get rattled under fire. . .
他就能杀了你
. . .like as not he'll kill you.
-如果对方速度更快--  -那他就会着急,就会失误
-But if the other fellow is quicker-- -Then he'll hurry and he'll miss.
看这儿
Look here.
这是我拔枪、瞄准、射击十码内目标的最快速度
That's as fast as l can draw, aim, hit anything more than 1 0 feet away.
除非这里是个谷仓
Unless it's a barn.
如果他要是没有失误呢?
But if he doesn't miss?
他就会杀了你
He'll kill you.
这就是为什么像鲍勃一样的危险人物比较少的原故了
That's why there's so few dangerous men around like Bob.
我也算危险人物
Like me.
如果对方还击,那就不太容易获胜了
lt ain't so easy to shoot a man if he's shooting back.
那会引起混乱
That'll flat rattle some folks.
让我给你看点儿东西
Let me show you something.
看这儿.拿着这个
Look here. Take that.
来呀,拿着
Go on, take it.
这是牢门钥匙
There's the key.
开枪打我...
Just shoot me. . .
然后你和鲍勃就能像小鸟一样自由了
. . .and you and Bob can ride on out of here free as birds.
-已经装弹药了?  -没装弹的枪有什么用?
-ls it loaded? -Wouldn't do any good if it wasn't.
首先,你得扳起扳机
First, you got to cock it.
来呀,扳起扳机
Go on, cock it.
现在你得瞄准
Now you got to point it.
快呀,瞄准呀
Go on. Point it.
现在要做的就是扣动扳机
Now all you got to do is pull the trigger.
感觉不错?
Hot, ain't it?
你还没把手指放到扳机上呢?
Didn't even put your finger on the trigger.
如果....
What if. . . .
如果我把枪给他?
What if l gave it to him?
给他
Give it to him.
把枪给他
我想他不会要的
l guess he don't want it.
不拿枪是对的
You were right not to take it.
不然我会杀了你
l'd have killed you.
下雨了
We could use some rain.
操他妈的鬼天气!
You no-good, goddamn pig-fucking whore!
让你受苦了,老马
Sorry, old horse.
我带这玩意本来是庆祝我们完成任务的
l brung this for when we kill them fellows.
看来我们现在就需要了
Figured we could use some now.
我不要.我可不想再碰那玩意了
Not me. l don't touch it no more.
-没事,现在在下雨.  -我知道现在在下雨!
-Come on, it's raining. -l know it's raining!
给那孩子点儿
Give some to the Kid.
你觉得那孩子真的杀了五个人?
You think that Kid really killed five men?
不
No.
当他说那两个治安官用枪指着你的时候...
When he talked about the time them deputies had the drop on you. . . .
我记的好象三个人,不是两人
l remember there was three men you shot, not two.
我现在不喜欢杀人了,内德!
l ain't like that no more, Ned!
我不再是一个喜欢杀人的疯子了
l ain't no crazy killing fool.
还觉得杀人很简单吗?
Still think it'll be easy to kill them cowboys?
让我们先不要淋雨吧
lf we don't drown first.
把这钥匙交给售票员
Give these keys to the conductor.
一出这个县,就让他把鲍勃的手铐解开
He can loose Bob's cuffs as soon as he's outside the county.
我的枪呢?
Got my pistols?
我想你知道,鲍勃...
l guess you know, Bob. . .
...如果我再看见你,我会就自卫开枪
. . .that if l see you again l'll just shoot in self-defense.
我可没有抢走你的传记作者!
l didn't steal your biographer!
是他自愿留下来的!
He's staying on his own account!
他能想走就走吗?
He can go stuff himself as well, can't he?!
大家受的罪还不多吗?
The plague on the whole stinking lot of you!
这里无法无德!
Without morals or laws!
个个都无耻下流!
And all you whores! You got no laws and no honor!
怪不得你们要移民美国!
lt's no wonder you all emigrated to America!
就因为英国容不下你们这些人
Because they wouldn't have you in England!
你们都是野蛮人!
You're a lot of savages!
你们都是同一族血腥的野蛮人!诅咒你们!
You're all a bunch of bloody savages! A curse on you!
小比尔对这个英国人这么做...
Nobody's going to come. . .
应该没人会来了
. . .after what Little Bill done to that Englishman.
黛利拉,你就不能去擦擦桌子?
Delilah, can't you get them tables clean?
把你的脸遮起来,如果有人愿干你,你就不用去干活了
Cover your face, somebody might hump you and you wouldn't have to clean.
-那个遮脸的东西叫什么来着?   -面纱
-What do they call that face cover? -A veil.
是的,去弄个面纱!
Yeah. Get a veil!
要下雨了
Rain's coming.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
你确定?
You sure?
你没事吧,威尔?
You all right, Will?
有人点你
Fellow asking for you.
今晚?你不是开玩笑吧?
Tonight? You ain't joshing?
这边,小姐
This way, mister.
这种天气还出来,真是疯了
Must be randy as hell to come out in this shit.
“不,不!你错了,小比尔”!他说
''No, no! You're wrong, Little Bill'' ! he said.
“那家伙不是卷发.那家伙是是平头."
''That's not a Curly J. That's a Bobbed J! ''
他肯定是改了发型.我就对他说...
He had changed it over. And l said to him. . .
..."Jim,你真是个骗子和偷马贼!”
. . . ''Jim, you're a liar and a horse thief! ''
他发现没人帮助时,他就开始哭了...
When he saw nobody would help him, he started crying. . .
一边抽泣,一边求请
. . .and sobbing and just carrying on.
他说,“上帝,求求你了,不要杀我,比尔!"
He said, ''God, please, don't kill me, Bill! ''
我说："你真让我恶心...."
So l said, ''Jim, it makes me sick. . . ''
打开窗?
Open the window, will you?
“看到一个带两把手枪,一把来福枪的的家伙....
'' . . .to see a man carrying two pistols and a Henry rifle. . .
竟然哭成这样.”
. . .and crying like a damn baby. ''
-你杀了他?  -没有
-So you killed him? -No.
我应该杀他的
But l should have.
我不该对他们这么好的
l can't abide them kind.
你看他们在酒馆里的丑态
You see them in the taverns.
纵欲、酗酒
Tramps and drunk teamsters.
疯狂的矿工
Crazed miners.
到处放枪,好象他们都是坏人
Sporting their pistols and acting like they was bad men.
一点胆量也没有,做个坏人也不配
But without any sand or character. Not even any bad character.
我不喜欢杀手
l do not like assassins.
还有那些无胆的人
Or men of low character.
就像你的朋友,英国人鲍勃
Like your friend, English Bob.
可是,鲍勃可不是个懦夫
But, now Bob was no coward.
他不会哭,也不会求情--
He wouldn't cry and carry on like that--
治安官...
Sheriff. . . .
我没有其它的容器了
l don't have any more receptacles.
你可以把那个建屋的木匠吊死
Maybe you should hang the carpenter.
我这样说是因为....你吊死...
l was just saying because of the. . . . You hang. . . .
没事了
Doesn't matter.
操?
What the hell?
这种鬼天也有人来!
On a night like this!
-是谁?  -比尔,是我,副治安官查理·赫克
-Who the hell is it? -Deputy Charley Hecker, Bill.
有三个人进了镇.他们去了格里利的啤酒馆
Three fellows just come into town, Bill. They're down to Greely's.
有两人拿着枪
There's two of them got guns.
那小子去干什么了?
What the hell's keeping that Kid?
没事,他会回来的--
You don't suppose he's up--
天啊,威尔!
Jesus, Will!
你看起来脸色很差
You look like shit.
你还记的老鹰Hendershot吗?
You remember Eagle 亨德肖特?
我看见他了
l saw him.
威尔,他已经死了
Will, he's dead.
不,我看见他,内德
No, l saw him, Ned.
他的脑袋被打烂了.你能看到脑浆
His head was broke open. You could see inside of it.
天啊!你发烧了
Jesus! You got a fever.
-喝杯酒.  -虫子从里面爬出来
-Take a drink, will you? -Worms were coming out.
我得去看看那小子到底干什么去了?
Look, l'm going up to see what's keeping the Kid.
得从那些浪妞那里要点预付款
Must be getting an advance from one of the sporting ladies.
如果我要...
lf l was to. . . .
如果能行,那我自己就花点时间...
lf it worked out that l could take a little time for myself. . . .
我是说你不...
l mean you wouldn't. . . .
我想你不愿来
l guess you don't want to come.
交出你的枪
Give me the pistol.
我说了交出你的枪
l says give me over your pistol.
我没醉
l ain't drunk.
法律规定你必须上交你的武器...
Ordinance says you got to turn in your firearms to my office. . .
...不管白天还是晚上
. . .day or night.
我想因为天气的缘故,你没看见那布告牌
l guess you didn't see the sign, because of the weather.
没有
No.
但我没有..
But l ain't. . . .
我没有武器
l ain't armed.
你那些在楼上的朋友呢?他们带枪了吗?
What about your friends upstairs. They got any pistols?
他们也没有带枪
They ain't armed either.
你的酒溅出来了
Spilled your whiskey.
你叫什么?
What's your name?
William.
William. . .
...亨德肖特
. . .Hendershot.
好的,威廉·亨德肖特先生...
Well, Mr. William 亨德肖特. . .
...如果我说你他妈的是个骗子会怎么样?
. . .what if l was to say you was a no-good son of a bitching liar?
如果我说你是个胆小鬼会怎么样?
And if l was to say you shit in your pants because of a cowardly soul. . .
....我肯定你马上就要掏枪杀我
. . .l bet you'd show me that pistol quick and kill me.
是不是这样?
lsn't that so?
我想可能吧
Maybe, l guess.
但是,事实上...
But the fact is. . .
...我没有带枪
. . .l ain't carrying no firearm.
起来
Get up.
这是什么,是蛇吗?
What's this for, snakes and such?
我们这里可没什么蛇,亨德肖特先生
We don't have any snakes in here, Mr. Hendershot.
要么没装弹,要么就是弹药湿了?
lt ain't loaded or. . . . Powder's wet?
你看见了吗,比彻姆先生?
You see, Mr. Beauchamp?
这就是我说的垃圾!
This is the trash l was speaking of!
哪的酒吧里都有这种人!
They're in all the saloons in all your prosperous communities!
在威奇塔有!
Wichita!
在夏延有!
Over in Cheyenne!
在阿比林有!
Abilene!
但在大威士忌镇没有
But not in the town of Big Whiskey.
快!你知道该怎么对威尔说了吧
Hurry up! You know what to tell Bill.
找那棵大松树.错过那棵树,你们就完了
Look for that lone pine. Miss the pike, you won't find it.
不用穿衬衣了!只把靴子穿好就行了!
Forget the shirt! Put the boots on!
-我们要不要去救威尔?  -快走吧,孩子!
-What are we going to do about Will? -Come on, Kid!
希望马还在那儿!
Let's hope them horses are still there!
让他出去,W.W
Let the man out, W.W.
他受够了大威士忌镇的“热情”了
He's desiring to leave the hospitality of Big Whiskey behind him.
别激动!
Easy!
-她也是为了赚钱.  -他们怎么会从后窗跑了的?
-She's got to turn a dollar a time. -Why'd they lit out the back window?
他们看见你在打他们的朋友
They seen you beating on their friend.
-说实话,他们是来打台球的.  -打台球?
-They come for the billiards, honest. -Billiards?!
-他们只是经过这里?   -他们经过这里去Buford贸易站
-They were just passing through here? -They was going to Fort Buford.
你打了一个无辜的人
You kicked the shit out of an innocent man.
无辜?
lnnocent?
无辜什么?
lnnocent of what?
你以前也被人打成这样过?
You done this before?
很多次
Plenty times.
他的枪眼肯定是堵住了
His pistol must've jammed.
把蜡烛拿近点儿.我看不清
Here. Bring that candle in closer. l can't see.
如果他开枪,就不会被打了
He wouldn't take no beating if it hadn't jammed.
他应该反抗的
He wouldn't give it over and not shoot.
他看起来情况不妙
He don't look so good.
昨天他连枪都没拔?
He didn't even pull his pistol?
-小子,他没你这么硬汉?  -我肯定会拔枪
-He ain't as tough as you, Kid. -l'd have pulled my pistol.
你当然!爬窗户逃走你最快!
You did! Out of the lady and out the window!
-这是你的主意!我--  -我们得走了
-That was your idea! l-- -We got to go.
什么?我还想多一份预付款
What? l'm ready for another advance.
-你会都用光的.  -事成之前没有预付款了
-You'll use it all up. -No more advances on what's not done.
甜心,我们只是在等天气好转!
Sweetheart, we're just waiting on this weather to clear!
我们需要更多的食物!差不多吃三天的食物!
We're going to need more food! About three days' worth.
三天?
Three days?
我们明天就能杀了他们
We can kill them tomorrow.
-没有他,我谁也不杀.  -我们不需要他,我们两个就行
-l don't kill nobody without him. -We don't need him! We can do it.
况且..
Besides. . .
...他也在就是个受了伤的农民
. . .he ain't nothing but a broken-down pig farmer.
我们早上会派人来送吃的和一些威士忌!
One of us'll bring food in the morning, and some whiskey too!
如果有药也拿来吧!
And some medicine if you got any!
听到这声你不觉得恶心吗?
Don't it make you sick hearing him?
不要让这些女士们担心!
Don't you ladies worry!
我和内德会为你杀了那两个混蛋的!
Me and Ned will kill them two sons of bitches for you!
克劳迪娅
Claudia.
-克劳迪娅不在这儿.  -是你吗?内德
-Claudia's not here. -ls that you, Ned?
我看见他了
l seen him.
我看见死神了
l seen the Angel of Death.
我看见一条河,内德
l seen a river, Ned.
-他长着一双蛇眼.  -谁长一双蛇眼?
-He's got snake eyes. -Who's got snake eyes?
是死神
lt's the Angel of Death.
我害怕死亡
l'm scared of dying.
放松,伙计
Easy, partner.
我要去见克劳迪娅了
l seen Claudia too.
你能见到克劳迪娅,不是很好吗?
That's good you saw Claudia, ain't it?
她脸上都是虫子
Her face was all covered with worms.
内德,我害怕
Ned, l'm scared.
我要死了
l'm dying.
不要告诉任何人
No, don't tell nobody.
不要告诉我的孩子...
Don't tell my kids. . .
我以前的所做所为.你听见没?
. . .none of the things l done. You hear?
好的,威尔
All right, Will.
他要死了,是吧?
He's gonna die, ain't he?
可能
Maybe.
看来是的?
Supposing he does?
我们会埋了他
We'll bury him.
我不是这个意思
That ain't what l mean.
你的意思是想我帮你去杀那两个牛仔?
You mean will l help you kill them cowboys?
我可识不出他们两个
l can't spot them myself.
但你行
But you could.
那个大块头,我打赌你能在半里外就把他识出来
That big bastard, you could spot him a half-mile off, l bet.
如果我找出来了?
And if l spot him?
那我就会上去开枪
Then l ride up close and shoot him.
就像这样?
Just like that?
我是一个杀手.我以前就是这么做的
l'm a damn killer. l done it before.
我当杀手比他强的多
l'm more of a killer than he is.
是吗?
Yeah?
我还以为是个天使!
l thought you was an angel.
你没死
You ain't dead.
那些家伙...
Some big fellow. . .
...把我踢的半死
. . .kicked the hell out of me.
我现在应该长的像你一样了
l must look like you now.
你看起来不像我
You don't look nothing like me.
无意冒犯
No offense meant.
你一定是那个被牛仔割伤的女孩
You got to be the one those cowboys cut up.
我的搭档,内德和那小子在....
My partners, Ned and that Kid. . .
...在附近吗?
. . .they around?
你退烧的时候,他们就去打听消息了
They went out scouting when your fever broke.
打听消息?
Scouting?
就在T牧场外面...
Out to the Bar T. . .
...找他们
. . .looking for them.
我在这里多久了?
How long l been here?
三天了
Three days.
你饿不饿....?
Are you hungry or. . . .
三天?
Three days?
我本来应该...
l ought to be. . . .
我想我死了
l thought l was gone.
我本来不会注意这种山区里的...
l wouldn't normally pay no notice to high country like this. . .
...树的.但我现在明显注意到了
. . .trees, but l'm sure noticing now.
还以为我肯定活不了了
Thought l was dying for sure.
我把你的帽子拿来了
l brought your hat.
你把它留在格里利啤酒馆里了
You left it down at Greely's.
谢谢你
Thanks.
那个治安官...
That sheriff. . . .
-他还在找我?  -小比尔?
-He still looking for me? -Little Bill?
不,他认为你们往南走了
No, he thinks you went south.
你真的准备去杀死那两个牛仔?
Are you really going to kill them cowboys?
我想是的
l guess.
还有赏金吧?
Still a payment coming, isn't there?
他们两个,你的朋友...
Them other two, your friends. . .
...他们已经拿了预付款
. . .they been taking advances on the payment.
预付款?
Advances?
免费的
Free ones.
爱丽丝和苏姬让他们免费玩
Alice and Silky been giving them free ones.
我知道了
l see.
你想要一次免费的吗?
Would you like a free one?
我想不要
l guess not.
我不是说和我.我是说...
l didn't mean with me. l meant. . .
...爱丽丝和苏姬愿意让你免费玩一次,如果你愿意的话
. . .Alice and Silky would be happy to give you a free one if you wanted.
我就是这意思
That's all l meant.
我不是说..
l didn't mean. . .
...因为你被割伤了就不愿和你玩
. . .l didn't want a free one because you been cut up and all.
刚才我说的,你长的象我,根本是胡说八道
What l said about you looking like me, that ain't true.
你不象我那么丑
You ain't ugly like me.
只是我们俩都有疤痕
lt's just that we both got scars.
你是个漂亮的女士,如果我想要免费的...
You're a beautiful woman and if l wanted a free one. . .
...我愿意和你而不是和另外那两个
. . .l'd want it with you more than the other two.
只是因为...
lt's just that. . .
...我妻子的原故,我不能
. . .l can't on account of my wife.
你妻子?
Your wife?
我钦佩你
l admire you for that.
对你的妻子忠贞
For being true to your wife.
我认识很多男人..
l've known a lot of men. . .
...他们没有
. . .who weren't.
我想是的
l suppose.
她在堪萨斯?
ls she back in Kansas?
是的
Yeah.
她在看着我的孩子
She's watching over my young ones.
停下!
Hang on!
快去拿烙铁!
Get the damn iron!
天啊,伙计们!
Jesus, fellas!
天啊,我的腿断了!
Jesus, boys, my leg's broke!
我动不了了,兄弟们!
l'm pinned, boys!
最好杀了他,内德
Better finish him, Ned.
他还没死?你没杀了他?
He ain't dead? You didn't get him?
他杀了他小子的马
He got the boy's horse.
在那家伙跑出射程之前杀了他
Finish him before he gets clear.
他们在岩石后
Get behind them rocks.
我们过去!
Get over there!
发生了什么?他没死?
What happened? He ain't killed?!
怎么了?
What's going on?
他藏在岩石里,我们打不到他
He gets in those rocks, we won't get him.
-除非我们过去.  -什么岩石
-Unless we go down there. -What rocks?
你怎么不开枪?发生什么事了?
Why don't you shoot? What's going on?
开枪呀!
Shoot!
干这个我可不太在行
l ain't very good with one of these.
继续动,戴维!藏到岩石后面!
Keep going, Davey! The rocks!
你击中他没有?
Did you get him?
他在哪?
Where is he?
枪里还有几发子弹?
How many more shots do l have?
两发
Two.
你击中他了?
Did you get him?
拿,重新装弹
Here, reload this.
-你没击中.  -我击中了
-You missed him. -l got him.
他没死
He ain't killed.
可能死了,可能没死
Maybe, maybe not.
我想击中了他的内脏
Got him through the gut, l think.
觉得他要死了?
Think he'll die?
我们杀了他?
We killed him?
是的
Yeah.
我想我们是杀了他
We killed him, l guess.
我要死了,兄弟们!
l'm dying, boys!
混蛋,你就不应该去伤害那位女士!
Then you shouldn't have cut up no woman, you asshole!
天啊,我好渴!
Jesus, l'm so thirsty!
请给我点水!
Give me some water, please!
求求你了,斯利姆!
Please, Slim!
我在流血,斯利姆!
l'm bleeding, Slim!
快给他水,该死的!
Give him a drink of water, goddamn it!
给他水,看在上帝的份上!我们不要开枪
Give him some water, for chrissake! We ain't going to shoot!
你们不会开枪?
You ain't?
等一下,戴维仔
Hold on, Davey-boy!
现在我来了
Here l come now!
不要开枪,混蛋!
Don't shoot me, you bastards!
该死!
Shit!
他们给他喝水?
They take him water?
天啊, 乔尼! 他们射中了他!
Jesus, Johnny! They shot him!
现在等一下!
Hold on now!
你们这些杀人犯!你们杀了戴维仔!
You murdering bastards! You killed our Davey-boy!
我们什么时候回去?
When will we double back?
杀了那一个之后
After a ways.
我可不去
Not me.
-我们就要回堪萨斯了.  -我们得先杀了那个家伙
-l'm heading back down to Kansas. -We got to kill the other one first.
如果运气好,我们黄昏,要不就在黎明就能找到那家伙
With any luck, we'll find him by nightfall or in the morning.
我们会杀了他,然后带着钱回去
We'll shoot him and head back with the money.
-你想要这支斯宾塞步枪吗?  -现在可没时间退出
-Do you want the Spencer? -lt's no time to quit.
-这样走,你可一分钱没有.  -闭嘴!
-You'll lose your share. -Shut up!
我会去看你的,威尔.再见小子
l'll see you, Will. So long, Kid.
我现在枪法不行了
l ain't no good with that damn thing.
我和那小子会一起去农场,然后杀了那家伙
Me and the Kid'll head over to that ranch and we'll shoot him.
我们再和你会和,拿着钱,然后一起回家
We'll meet up with you, get our money, and go back together.
如果那家伙没回农场呢?
Suppose he don't go back to the ranch?
他不会去镇上,或者待在野外
He ain't going into town or stay out in the open country.
他一定会藏在农场里
He'll hole up at that ranch.
我可不愿等
l ain't waiting.
我会顺路看一看你的孩子
l'll look in on your young ones.
不用管那小子说的那些关于钱的话
Forget what the Kid said about the money and all.
我会把你的那份带回去
l'll bring yours.
小孩子不懂事
Kid's full of shit.
我在做一些修理
Doing some repairs up here.
他们杀了其中一牛仔
They killed one of them cowboys.
该死!
Shit!
帕森斯说他看见三个人日出之后向东走了
Parsons said he saw three men, right after sunup, headed east.
一个人骑着一匹暗褐色的马,另一个人骑着一匹有红斑的灰马
One was on a dun and another was on a flea-bitten grey.
他没看见第三个骑着什么马,可能是阿帕卢萨马
He didn't know what the third one was on, maybe an Appaloosa.
艾莫斯说他会去问一下县里愿不愿那些出那些马的草料钱
Amos says to ask if the county will pay for feed for all the horses.
威瑟斯彭说他不会赊帐卖给我们子弹了
Witherspoon won't sell us no more shells without pay.
见鬼,用我的狗去抵债吧
Hell, use my dogs!
县里应该负责
Then the county's got to be responsible.
我们一起去T牧场,确定一下剩下那个牛仔...
Get on out there to the Bar T and make sure that other cowboy. . .
...是不是待在那儿.并让他躲在那里
. . .stays put and don't expose himself.
我认为他们不会真的去做
l didn't think they'd really do it.
那你觉得他们从堪萨斯来,就为了玩我们
Think they come up from Kansas to fuck us?
那小子,只是个男孩,而剩下那个...
That Kid, he's just a boy and the other one. . .
...威尔,那个好心肠的,对他的妻子真是忠贞...
. . .Will, the nice one, being so true to his wife. . . .
妻子?他没老婆
Wife? He ain't got no wife.
-不,他有的.他--  -他没有
-Yes, he does. He-- -He ain't got no wife.
有也是已经死了的
Not above ground, anyways.
杀人犯妓女!
Murdering whores!
他那是....
He had it coming. . .
...罪有应得
. . .for what he done.
另外一个也快了
And the other one too!
他们两个都罪有应得!
Both of them for what they done!
我们抓住一个!
We got one!
我们抓住一个!就在牛溪外面!
We got one, Sheriff! Out by Cow Creek!
-他还活着吗?  -是的,还活着
-ls he alive? -Hell, yeah!
因为他们杀了我们一个兄弟,所以我们就一直在找他们
Bunch of us from Bar T went looking because they killed one of our own.
正遇上那混蛋骑着一匹杂色马向南走
Come across the bastard on a roan heading south.
他承认了?
He admit it?
没有,我想他会很快承认的.他身上带着一支斯宾塞来福枪
No. But l guess he will soon enough. Had a Spencer rifle on him.
他们揍他了吗?
They messing him up?
不算太严重
Little bit.
快去那儿.再查查剩下两个在哪?
Get out there. Find out what happened to those other two!
在那看见什么了,山羊?
See anything out there, Buck?
当然!看见有200多号人拿着来福枪
Hell, yes! Seen about 200 fellows packing rifles.
把那地方包围着.说想要奎克·迈克的屁股
Got the place surrounded. Say they want Quick Mike's ass.
我说,“多少钱?”他们说,“5...”我说,“....元”
l said, ''How much?'' They says, ''Five. '' l said, ''Dollars?''
他们说,“...分”
They said, ''Cents. ''
我说,“成交”
l said, ''Sold. ''
我不担心
Well, l ain't worried!
因为我有保护措施
Because l got me some protection.
-告诉我剩下的两个在哪?  -不
-Tell you where them others is? -Nope.
姓名?
Names?
只告诉了我们他的名字,内德 山地白杨
Only told us his name, Ned Roundtree.
带他进去
Bring him in.
你会告诉我和比彻姆先生..
You'll want to tell me and Mr. Beauchamp here. . .
...关于你和你那恶棍朋友的一切的
. . .all about your two villainous friends.
我想知道他们的名字和行踪
l'll want the names and whereabouts of those son of a bitches.
时机成熟
Sure is ripe.
再等一下时机会更好
Going to get a lot riper.
他还在那儿么?
Think he's still in there?
是的,他还在
He's in there.
他正守着他那些钱之类的宝贝呢
He's holding on to his shit like it was money.
他一定在
He's in there.
看见他就马上告诉我
Tell me right off if you see him.
你自己不开枪?
You won't shoot him your own self?
你可以开枪的
You can shoot him.
现在,你和昆西先生还有...
Now you and Mr. Quincy and. . . .
那个年轻人叫什么名字?
What was the young fellow's name?
埃尔罗伊·塔特
Elroy Tate.
不,刚才你可不是这么说的
No, that's not what you said.
见鬼,就是这么说的!
Hell, if it ain't!
不,你说...
No, you said. . .
..."埃尔罗伊·昆西来自麦迪森海特....
. . . ''Elroy 昆西 out of Medicine Hat. . .
...而亨利·塔特来自夏延.”
. . .and Henry Tate out of Cheyenne. ''
见鬼,我刚才说错了
Hell, if l did.
把那天和他们上床的妓女带来
Go get them whores that pumped these boys that night.
草莓爱丽丝和苏姬?
Strawberry Alice and Silky?
去呀,把他们带来!
Go on and get them!
那些妓女会说和你说的不一样的慌
Them whores are going to tell different lies than you.
如果她们说的真和你说的不一样的话...
And when their lies ain't the same as your lies. . . .
我不会去打那些妓女
l ain't going to hurt no woman.
我会打你
But l'm going to hurt you.
可不象刚才这么温柔....
Not gentle like before. . .
...将会很痛、很痛
. . .but bad.
你去哪?
Where you going?
-去拉屎.  -等我打完跟你去
-The shithouse. -Let me finish.
在我拉屎时保护我?
To protect me while l take a dump?
-你会被人伏击的?  -我会冲着他们放个屁
-You'll get bushwhacked. -l'll fart on them.
-我去.  -好的,你去帮我擦屁股吧,瑟斯蒂
-l'll go. -Yeah, you can wipe my ass, Thirsty.
鬼才跟你去呢.他这么没礼貌,活该被人打死
Hell with him. He ain't polite, he should get shot.
是他吗?
ls that him?
是的,就是他
Yeah, that's him.
好的,小子.快上,他是你的了
All right, Kid. Go get him. He's all yours.
有杀手!
Assassins!
开枪呀!
Shoot him!
快回来,该死的!
Come on, goddamn it!
杀了他没有?
Did you get him?
掩护我
Cover me.
-我看不见他们!  -只管开枪就行了
-l can't see them! -Just shoot!
这象不象以前的日子?
Was it like that in the old days?
大家们都骑马,开枪...
Everybody riding out, shooting. . .
...到处都是烟,乡亲们大叫,子弹到处飞?
. . .smoke all over, folks yelling, bullets whizzing by?
我想是的
l guess so.
该死,我还以为他们会追上我们
Shit, l thought they'd get us.
我还有点害怕
l was even scared a little.
不过只是一会儿
For a minute.
你以前害怕过吗?
You ever scared in them days?
我不记的了
l can't remember.
大部分时候,我都是醉的
l was drunk most of the time.
我对他混蛋开了三枪
l shot that fucker three times!
他在拉屎,正准备拿枪呢,我就动手了
He was taking a shit, went for his pistol and l blazed away.
第一枪...
First shot. . .
...就打中了他的右胸
. . .l got him right in the chest.
那是第一次
That was the first.
第一次什么?
First what?
我第一次杀人
First one l ever killed.
是吗?
Yeah?
你知道我过去说我杀过五个人?
You know how l said l shot five men?
是假的
lt weren't true.
那个拿刀的墨西哥人?
That Mexican with the knife?
我只是用铁铲伤了他的腿.我没杀他
l just busted his leg with a shovel. l didn't kill him or nothing.
你确定你已经杀了他
You sure killed the hell out of that fellow today.
是的,我确定
Hell, yeah!
我已经杀了那个混蛋,是吧?
Killed the hell out of him, didn't l?
开了三枪,他又在拉屎
Three shots and he was taking a shit.
喝口酒,小子
Take a drink, Kid.
上帝呀!
Jesus Christ!
真像在做梦!
lt don't seem real.
他真的不再呼吸了
How he ain't never breathing again, ever.
他真的死了
How he's dead.
另外一个也一样
And the other one too.
只是扣了一下扳机
On account of pulling a trigger.
杀人就是这么回事
lt's a hell of a thing, killing a man.
你拿走了他现有的...
You take away all he's got. . .
...和将有的一切
. . .and all he'll ever have.
我想他们已经经历了
l guess they had it coming.
我们每个人都会经历,小子
We all have it coming, Kid.
我一直在观察,你没有被跟踪
l was watching that you weren't followed.
苏姬和费思向东走了,有两个副治安官跟着她们
Silky and Faith rode off to the east and two deputies followed them.
-你想帮忙一起点这些钱吗?  -我相信你
-You want to help me count this? -l trust you.
可不要太相信我
Don't go trusting me too much.
实际上,我们要把内德那份一起拿出来
ln fact, we'll give Ned his share together.
我来替他拿着
You'll know l ain't holding out on you.
内德那一份?
Ned's share?
他往南边走了.我们会碰头的
He went south. We'll catch up.
他已经死了
He's dead.
你是什么意思,“死了”?
What do you mean, dead?
他昨天向南走了,他没死
He went south yesterday. He ain't dead.
他们杀了他,我以为你们知道的
They killed him. l thought you knew.
没有人杀内德!
Nobody killed Ned!
他什么人也没杀.他向南走了
He didn't kill anyone. He went south!
为什么有人要杀内德?
Why would anybody kill Ned?
谁杀了他?
Who killed him?
小比尔
Little Bill.
T牧场的人抓住了他...
The Bar T boys caught him. . .
...打他
. . .and he beat him up.
让他回答问题,又打他.这样他就死了
He was making him answer questions, beating him up. Then Ned just died.
他们给他定了个罪名,说他是杀手
They got a sign on him says he was a killer.
给他定了个罪名?
A sign on him?
就贴在格里利妓院门口
ln front of Greely's.
给他定了个罪名就贴在格里利妓院门口
A sign on him in front of Greely's!
他们问的...
These questions he was asking. . .
...到底是什么问题?
. . .what were they?
都是关于你和他的
About where you and him was.
然后又怎么样?
Then what?
一个牛仔进来说你们在厕所里杀了奎克·迈克
A cowboy come in saying you killed Quick Mike in the shithouse.
这样小比尔就杀了他?
So Little Bill killed him for what we done?
不是为这个
Not on purpose.
他打他打得更厉害了
But he started hurting him worse.
让他透露你们的事!
Making him tell stuff.
开始,内德不说
First, Ned wouldn't talk.
后来,小比尔打的他受不了了,他就说了你是谁
Then Little Bill hurt him so bad, he said who you was.
他说你是来自密苏里的威廉.芒尼
He said how you was really William Munny out of Missouri.
小比尔说,“就是那家伙....
Little Bill said, ''The same who dynamited
...69年的时候炸了铁路,死了不少妇女、儿童.”
. . .the railroad in '69, killing women and children?''
内德说你做了不少更坏的事.说你...
Ned said you done a lot worse. Said you was. . .
...比威尔·邦尼还冷血.说如果小比尔再敢打他的话...
. . .more cold-blooded than Will Bonney. Said if he hurt Ned again. . .
...你就会来杀了他,就像在70的杀死美国法警一样
. . .you'd come kill him like you killed the U.S. Marshal in '70.
这没吓倒他,是吧?
That didn't scare him, did it?
是的,先生
No, sir.
把你的斯科菲尔德手枪给我
Give me your Schofield.
为什么?
Why?
给我
Give it.
你想要,你就拿着吧
You want it, keep it.
我不要用它了
l won't use it.
我不会再杀人了
l won't kill nobody no more.
我可不像你,威尔
l ain't like you, Will.
你最好回去了,小姐
You better ride on back, Miss.
把这都拿去吧,都是你的了
Go on, keep all of it. lt's yours.
那你拿什么去买眼镜和衣服呢?
What about spectacles and fancy clothes?
我宁愿破衣烂衫的当个瞎子,也比死了好
l'd rather be blind and ragged than dead.
你不用担心,小子.我不会杀了你
You don't have to worry, Kid. l ain't going to kill you.
你是我唯一的朋友
You're the only friend l got.
拿着你自己那份,然后把我那份和内德那份给我的孩子
Take this money and give my share and Ned's share to my kids.
告诉他们如果我一星期内没回去,就把其中的一半给萨利
Tell them if l ain't back in a week, to give half to Sally.
其余的你拿着,去买幅眼镜吧
You keep the rest. Get them spectacles.
你要去杀小比尔?
You'll go kill Little Bill?
待在人们的视线之外.会有不少人要出来吊死你
Stay clear of folks you see. There'll be a lot out to hang you.
去吧
Get going.
我只说一次,说过就不准再问
l'll say this just one more time, so don't ask me again!
今天巡逻的人喝一杯县里出钱的酒
Those on today's posse got one drink coming from the county budget!
昨天巡逻的人也喝一杯
And those who rode yesterday get one for that too.
等一下!
Hold it!
这样就是两杯了.这以后的酒钱,就要你们自己出了,听到没?
That's two! After that, it comes out of your own pocket! You hear?
-是的,先生.  -我们明天早起
-Yes, sir. -We'll pull out early in the morning.
我们要追他们到得州,所以不要喝太多酒
We'll chase them clear to Texas, so don't spend too much money.
我们分四队!
We'll divide up into four parties!
我们要搜遍那个区域里...
We'll hit all the farms, trails. . .
...的每一个农场,小路
. . .in a big circle.
我们总能找到几个...
We're bound to find somebody. . .
...见过那两个家伙的人
. . .who seen these skunks.
谁是这儿的主人?
Who owns this shithole?
你,肥仔,说话
You, fat man. Speak up.
这儿是我的
l own this establishment.
我花了一千块钱从格里利手里买的
l bought it from Greely for $1 ,000.
最好走开
Better clear out.
等下!
Hold it!
先生,你他妈的是个懦夫!
Sir, you are a cowardly son of a bitch!
你刚才杀了一个手无寸铁之人
You just shot an unarmed man.
他应该拿武器的...
He should've armed himself. . .
...如果他用我朋友的尸体来装饰酒吧
. . .if he decorated his saloon with my friend.
你应该就是密苏里的妇儒杀手....
You'd be William Munny out of Missouri. . .
...威廉.芒尼吧
. . .killer of women and children.
正确
That's right.
我杀女人和孩子
l killed women and children.
只要能走、能爬的东西,我就杀
Killed just about everything that walks or crawls.
我就是来杀你的, 小比尔
And l'm here to kill you, Little Bill.
为你对内德所做的一切
For what you did to Ned.
其它人最好走开
You boys better move away.
好的,先生.他只剩一发子弹了
All right, gentlemen. He's got one barrel left.
等他开了枪后,用你们的手枪..
When he fires it, use your pistols. . .
...把他打成马蜂窝!
. . .and shoot him down like the mangy scoundrel he is!
卡壳了!杀了这个混蛋!
Misfire! Kill the son of a bitch!
谁不想死,就从后面走出来
Any man don't want to get killed, better clear on out the back.
我中枪了,我中枪了
l'm shot! l'm shot!
你没中枪
You ain't shot.
我没有枪,我没有武器
l don't have a gun. l am not armed.
捡起那支来福枪
Pick up that rifle.
捡起来
Pick it up.
还有子弹
Shells too.
你杀了小比尔
You killed Little Bill.
你没武器?
You ain't armed?
我没武装.我没有枪
l'm not. l don't have a gun.
我从来不拿枪.我是个作家
l've never had a gun. l'm a writer!
作家?
A writer?
-写信?  -是写书
-Letters and such? -Books.
写书
Books.
真不敢相信,你杀了五个人,赤手空拳
l don't believe it, you killed five men. Single-handed.
这是个斯宾塞来福枪,对吧?
That's a Spencer rifle, right?
你先杀谁?
Who'd you kill first?
“当遇到高手时...
''When confronted by superior numbers. . .
...有经验的枪手会先杀枪法最好之人."
. . .an experienced gunfighter will fire on the best shot first. ''
这是小比尔说的.你应该先杀了他吧
Little Bill said that. You probably killed him first.
从顺序上来说,我真幸运
l was lucky in the order.
枪战时,我总是很幸运
l'm always lucky when it comes to killing folks.
谁是下一个?克莱德,对吧?
Who was next? Clyde, right?
你已经杀了克莱德,或者是副治安官安迪--
You killed Clyde, or it was Deputy Andy--
我只能告诉你谁是最后一个
All l can tell you is who'll be last.
我不该死
l don't deserve this.
像这样死
To die like this.
我在建房子呢
l was building a house.
“该不该”和这没关系
Deserve's got nothing to do with it.
我们在地狱里再见吧,威廉.芒尼
l'll see you in hell, William Munny.
好的,我出来了!
All right, l'm coming out!
我看见谁就杀谁!
Any man l see out there, l'll kill him!
如果有人敢向我开枪...
Anyone takes a shot at me. . .
...我不仅要杀他,还要杀他的老婆和朋友
. . .l'm not only going to kill him, but his wife and all his friends.
...还要把他的房子烧了
. . .and burn his damn house down!
最好没人开枪!
Nobody better shoot!
查理,快开枪呀
Charley, go ahead. Shoot him!
我不能
l can't.
见鬼,不.我不能,我可不是副治安官
Hell, no! l ain't no deputy!
你们最好今晚就把内德埋了
You better bury Ned right!
你们最好别再碰那些妓女了!
You better not cut up nor otherwise harm no whores!
不然,我会回来杀光你们这些混蛋
Or l'll come back and kill every one of you sons of bitches.
多年以后，
安索尼娅费瑟斯夫人
艰苦跋涉前往霍奇曼县，
探望她唯一女儿的最后安息之地
威廉早就与孩子们失踪了，
有人说他到了旧金山，
在干货市场上生意兴隆
但没有任何东西能向费瑟斯太太
解释,为什么她唯一的女儿
会下嫁一个众所周知的小偷和凶手，
一个臭名昭著恶毒的、无节制的男人
导演&制作
克林特·伊斯特伍德
编 剧
大卫·韦伯·皮普尔斯
制 片
大卫·沃德斯
摄 影
杰克·N·格林
主演
克林特·伊斯特伍德
吉恩·哈克曼
摩根·弗里曼